Here we're not going to discuss how to solve these feasibility check exactly.
这里我们不讨论如何精确地解决这些可行性检测问题
But I want to give you a few hints about how to
但是我想要给大家一些提示
do some initial validation for your trajectory.
关于为你的轨迹做一些最初的校验
In order to do so, we're going to neglect
要做这个 我们会忽略道路的弯曲
the curvature of the road and assume it is locally straight.
假定道路是直的
Regarding longitudinal acceleration, we make
而在纵向加速度方面
the additional assumption that our heading is pretty much aligned with the road.
我们做进一步假定 假定我们的车头和道路是平行的
This allows us to say that S doubled dots is the longitude acceleration of the car.
这样的话 我们可以说双点修饰的 S 是汽车的纵向加速度
Therefore, we need to check that at any point of the trajectory,
因此 我们需要在轨迹的每一点去检测
this acceleration is less than
是否这个加速度小于
the maximum acceleration that the engine would need to supply,
引擎可提供的最大加速度值
and more than the maximum braking deceleration of the car.
并大于汽车的最大减速停车值
Right now, this could be a fixed value.
现在 这是一个固定值
In real life however,
然而 在实践中
this should probably be computed using information about the friction of the road.
这个值也许需要计算得出 计算过程需要用到路面的摩擦力信息
Similarly, for lateral acceleration,
类似地 对于横向加速度
we can check that all d double dot values are less than
我们可以检测所有的双点 d  是否小于
a fixed lateral acceleration value that can be set for comfort,
一个固定的横向加速值 那个值可以很容易设定
or to avoid any risk of rollover in our car.
以避免汽车产生侧翻动作
Regarding steering angle, the bicycle model tells us that there's
有关倾斜角 自行车模式告诉我们
a nice relationship between the steering angle of
在倾斜角和汽车运行半径之间
the car and the radius of the circle of curvature,
存在着很大的相关性
where L is the distance between the wheel axis and R is the circle radius.
这里 L 是轮轴间距 R 是圆的半径
The curvature is then given by this formula,
曲线通过这个方程给定
and therefore the maximum curvature allowed at
这样在任意点允许的最大曲率
any point of the trajectory is given by this equation.
由这个等式给定
If you remember, in the reading assignment about [inaudible]
大家回想下 在阅读材料中
the curvature for path is defined like this,
路径的曲率是像这样定义的
where Δφi is the heading difference between two points of
这里 Δφi 是在轨迹上两点之间的最大变化值
the trajectory and Δχi is the distance between them.
而 Δχi 则是两点间距离
Finally the velocity is checked against
最后 我们会依据地图或者行为层指定的值
values specified by the map or the behavioral layer.
来进行速度检测
For example, we could use the speed limit of the road in most cases.
例如 在大部分情况下 我们能使用道路的限速值
That gives us a maximal velocity but also sometimes,
那样 我们可以得到一个最大速度值 但同时在一些其他情况下
we need a minimal velocity like on
比如 在高速路上 我们需要一个最小速度值
highways where we don't want to drive too slow or we're backing up,
那种情况下 我们不想行驶的特别慢 或者我们在倒车
negative S dot is not allowed.
S 点的值不允许为负值